<planning_inputs>
  <summary>
    <goal>The calendar add-task modal must use existing backlog tasks only (no free-form input). Cards may optionally reference a backlog task via a nullable FK (schedule_task_cards.task_id → backlog_tasks.id), with field inheritance and delete guards.</goal>
    <diff_summary>Branch feature/2a5f914b-171f-4ccc-a5c0-11f959f3900a (HEAD c0e3997, 3 commits above base de79b9d). Cumulative diff across 16 files: migration (010_add_schedule_card_task_id.sql), SQL queries (daily_schedule.sql adds task_id column, TaskExists, TaskHasScheduleCards, GetTaskByIDForRef), sqlc-generated Go (daily_schedule.sql.go), store layer (store.go adds inheritance in CreateScheduleCard + UpdateScheduleCard, delete guard in DeleteTask, TaskID in buildTaskCardResponse, TaskExists/TaskHasScheduleCards methods), API layer (daily_schedule.go adds TaskId to input/output structs, conditional validation, TaskExists call; tasks.go adds ErrTaskHasScheduleCards sentinel + 400 handler), store interface (store.go adds TaskExists, TaskHasScheduleCards), mock store (store_mock_test.go adds scheduleTaskRefs map, inheritance in both CreateScheduleCard and UpdateScheduleCard, TaskHasScheduleCards), backend tests (main_test.go adds 7 new test functions covering create with valid/invalid/override taskId, delete with references, update preserves inheritance, daily schedule reflection, and failing-store interface compliance), frontend types (types.gen.ts, openapi-snapshot.json), CalendarView.vue (replaces rooms query → task backlog query, task selector with search, edit modal branches on taskId presence), DailySchedule.vue (adds From backlog badge for referenced cards), useDailySchedule.ts (adds taskId to ScheduleTaskCard interface), CalendarView.spec.ts (rewritten from room-select tests to task-selector + edit-modal tests).</diff_summary>
    <durable_task_comment_status>present</durable_task_comment_status>
  </summary>

  <review_feedback>

    <!-- === Comment 1 — swarm-reviewer (approved) === -->
    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-reviewer</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>fcf0e8d6-3262-4e03-a550-99376b31d159</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-16T20:36:27Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>Approved. All requirements satisfied, two critical bugs fixed (UpdateScheduleCard field erasure, DeleteTask 500 vs 400). Full stack covered: migration, CRUD, delete protection, frontend UX, tests. Merge recommended.</request>
      <impacted_code>Global — covers all files in the diff.</impacted_code>
      <notes>This is the latest review round (most recent timestamp). Outcome: approved. No remaining issues raised.</notes>
    </item>

    <!-- === Comment 2 — swarm-lead-dev (needs_work) — PENDING ISSUES === -->
    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-lead-dev</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>07f3dd1e-445f-4543-a1c4-49fcc8aa259c</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-16T20:35:59Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>Fix TOCTOU race in inheritance resolution (GetTaskByIDForRef called outside transaction in CreateScheduleCard/UpdateScheduleCard). Fix silent taskId-clearing path in UpdateScheduleCard when input.TaskId is empty but card has existing taskId. Fix mock inconsistency that masks bugs. Add test coverage for edge cases: changing taskId on existing card, backend store-level validation failures.</request>
      <impacted_code>backend/store.go: CreateScheduleCard (~line 643), UpdateScheduleCard (~line 741): GetTaskByIDForRef runs before pgxTx.Begin(). backend/store_mock_test.go: mock CreateScheduleCard/UpdateScheduleCard may not match real store edge-case behavior.</impacted_code>
      <notes>REPEATED/UNRESOLVED from this review round. Four concrete concerns remain: (1) TOCTOU race — inheritance resolution reads the task outside the transaction, then uses those values inside; the FK constraint protects referential integrity, but stale values could be written. (2) Silent taskId clearing — UpdateScheduleCard writes TaskID: pgtype.Text{String: input.TaskId, Valid: input.TaskId != ""}. When frontend omits taskId for a referenced card (or API client sends empty), the reference is silently erased. The frontend currently always sends taskId for referenced cards, but direct API callers could trigger this. (3) Mock might not match real-store behavior for edge cases. (4) No test for changing taskId or removing taskId from a referenced card, or store-level FK validation failures.</notes>
    </item>

    <!-- === Comment 3 — swarm-architect (approved, with gap) === -->
    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-architect</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>5d5c518a-7056-43cf-abe7-79b5f33f577d</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-16T20:35:17Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>Add architecture documentation for the task-card inheritance domain model.</request>
      <impacted_code>Documentation files — workspace.c4 or ARCHITECTURE.md or equivalent.</impacted_code>
      <notes>Only gap identified by the architect review: missing architecture docs describing how inheritance works for task-card references. Not a code change, but a documentation gap.</notes>
    </item>

    <!-- === Comment 4 — swarm-lead-dev (needs_work) — RESOLVED === -->
    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-lead-dev</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>6d65a97b-4d40-4253-9a87-f5fc3df2d079</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-16T20:19:27Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>Fix the data corruption bug in UpdateScheduleCard: when frontend omits title/priority/roomArea/peopleNeeded for taskId-linked card edits, backend unconditionally writes empty/zero values to SQL. Add inheritance logic similar to CreateScheduleCard (resolve from GetTaskByIDForRef for empty input fields).</request>
      <impacted_code>backend/store.go: UpdateScheduleCard function — the function body passed input.Title/Priority/RoomArea/PeopleNeeded directly to tx.UpdateScheduleCard without resolving from referenced task.</impacted_code>
      <notes>RESOLVED at HEAD c0e3997. The latest store.go diff shows inheritance logic added to UpdateScheduleCard (lines ~741-764), identical to CreateScheduleCard pattern.</notes>
    </item>

    <!-- === Comment 5 — swarm-architect (approved) === -->
    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-architect</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>96f9a238-5dc4-4b50-b3b2-1f7610186357</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-16T20:19:16Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>Approved. Changes structurally sound. Calendar add-task modal uses existing backlog tasks (not free-form) while preserving backward compatibility for editing legacy schedule cards without taskId.</request>
      <impacted_code>Global architecture — component boundaries, data flow, dependency directions respected.</impacted_code>
      <notes>Architect review at an earlier round. No issues raised. Architecture considered sound.</notes>
    </item>

    <!-- === Comment 6 — swarm-reviewer (needs_work) — RESOLVED === -->
    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-reviewer</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>1edb858a-f61b-4607-a8e9-a82b5a211772</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-16T20:19:07Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>Fix critical UpdateScheduleCard field erasure bug. Add three backend tests: TestCreateScheduleCardWithValidTaskId, TestCreateScheduleCardWithInvalidTaskId, TestCreateScheduleCardWithTaskIdAndOverrides. Add taskId assertion in daily-schedule reflection test (TestScheduleCardWriteReflectsInDailySchedule or separate TestTaskIdReflectsInDailySchedule).</request>
      <impacted_code>backend/store.go:730 (UpdateScheduleCard). backend/main_test.go (missing tests for taskId creation and daily-schedule taskId reflection).</impacted_code>
      <notes>ALL RESOLVED at HEAD c0e3997. UpdateScheduleCard has inheritance logic. Tests added: TestCreateScheduleCardWithValidTaskId, TestCreateScheduleCardWithInvalidTaskId, TestCreateScheduleCardWithTaskIdAndOverrides, TestTaskIdReflectsInDailySchedule, and TestScheduleCardWriteReflectsInDailySchedule updated to assert taskId nil for unreferenced cards.</notes>
    </item>

    <!-- === Comment 7 — swarm-reviewer (needs_work) — RESOLVED === -->
    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-reviewer</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>8966c534-3676-461f-9b9b-7559b3c1ed2a</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-16T20:01:10Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>Fix critical: edit modal for unreferenced (legacy) cards broken — shows task selector instead of free-form fields. Fix warning: DeleteTask returns 500 instead of 400. Fix info: indentation in store.go:300. Fix info: add frontend tests for create mutation body and edit modal paths.</request>
      <impacted_code>frontend/src/calendar/CalendarView.vue (edit modal template and handleSubmit for unreferenced path). backend/api/tasks.go (DeleteTask error handling). backend/store.go:300 (indentation). frontend/src/calendar/__tests__/CalendarView.spec.ts (missing tests).</impacted_code>
      <notes>ALL RESOLVED at HEAD c0e3997. Edit modal branches on taskId: referenced cards show read-only task info, unreferenced show free-form fields. DeleteTask uses ErrTaskHasScheduleCards sentinel → 400. Indentation at ~line 300 is consistent (3 tabs). Tests added for create mutation body and both edit modal paths.</notes>
    </item>

    <!-- === Comment 8 — swarm-lead-dev (needs_work) — RESOLVED === -->
    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-lead-dev</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>cb2b7e5d-f44c-4105-b48f-d490edf3609b</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-16T20:00:01Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>Fix two critical bugs in frontend form submission logic. Add sufficient test coverage for both backend validation paths and frontend interactions.</request>
      <impacted_code>frontend/src/calendar/CalendarView.vue (handleSubmit for create and edit). backend/main_test.go and frontend CalendarView.spec.ts (test coverage).</impacted_code>
      <notes>RESOLVED at HEAD c0e3997. Same issues as Comment 7's edit modal + Comment 6's backend tests. All now fixed.</notes>
    </item>

    <!-- === Comment 9 — swarm-architect (approved) === -->
    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-architect</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>3d1f2549-a39a-42cc-a6a8-bdf3abf4251b</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-16T19:59:27Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>Approved. Architecture structurally sound. Foreign key from schedule_task_cards.task_id to backlog_tasks.id aligns with existing workspace.c4 model (calendar places ready tasks from taskData).</request>
      <impacted_code>Architecture layer — FK relationship, field inheritance, validation, referential integrity.</impacted_code>
      <notes>Earliest architect review. No issues.</notes>
    </item>

    <!-- === Comment 10 — swarm-lead-dev (finished) === -->
    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-lead-dev</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>54b4a9e8-f53a-4ed6-ba4e-5c59273ca2c3</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-16T19:10:19Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>Finished — prior task execution completed.</request>
      <impacted_code>N/A — workflow metadata only.</impacted_code>
      <notes>Not review feedback. Marks the end of a prior agent run.</notes>
    </item>

  </review_feedback>

  <relevant_code_areas>
    <code_area>
      <path>backend/store.go</path>
      <reason>Core store logic. CreateScheduleCard (~line 634) and UpdateScheduleCard (~line 718): inheritance resolution runs before the database transaction (TOCTOU concern). UpdateScheduleCard writes input.TaskId directly without preserving existing taskId when input is empty (silent clearing concern). buildTaskCardResponse (~line 853) handles TaskID pgtype.Text → *string conversion.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>backend/api/daily_schedule.go</path>
      <reason>API-level validation and input types. CreateScheduleCardRequestBody now has conditional validation (fields required only when taskId absent). TaskExists is called from validation. CreateScheduleCardInput and UpdateScheduleCardInput both pass TaskId through.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>backend/api/tasks.go</path>
      <reason>DeleteTask handler returns 400 for ErrTaskHasScheduleCards (already fixed). ErrTaskHasScheduleCards sentinel defined here.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>backend/api/store.go</path>
      <reason>Store interface — TaskExists and TaskHasScheduleCards methods added.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>backend/store_mock_test.go</path>
      <password>true</password>
      <reason>Mock store implementation must match real-store behavior faithfully. Current diff shows inheritance logic mirrors real store, plus scheduleTaskRefs map for TaskHasScheduleCards alignment.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>backend/db/daily_schedule.sql.go</path>
      <reason>sqlc-generated code. TaskID column added to all schedule card queries (CreateScheduleCard, UpdateScheduleCard, GetScheduleCardByID, GetDailyScheduleTaskCards). New queries: TaskExists, TaskHasScheduleCards, GetTaskByIDForRef.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>backend/db/migrations/010_add_schedule_card_task_id.sql</path>
      <reason>Database migration: ALTER TABLE schedule_task_cards ADD COLUMN task_id TEXT REFERENCES backlog_tasks(id) ON DELETE RESTRICT, plus index.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>backend/main_test.go</path>
      <reason>Test coverage for taskId creation (valid, invalid, overrides), delete with references, update preserves inheritance, daily schedule reflection. Also failingStore interface compliance (TaskExists, TaskHasScheduleCards return errTestFailure). No test for: changing taskId on existing card, removing taskId from referenced card, store-level FK validation failures.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>frontend/src/calendar/CalendarView.vue</path>
      <reason>Main frontend component. Uses useTaskBacklog instead of listRoomsQuery. Task selector with search in create mode. Edit mode branches on card.taskId: referenced cards show read-only task info, unreferenced show free-form fields. handleSubmit sends taskId for referenced cards, free-form fields for unreferenced.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>frontend/src/calendar/__tests__/CalendarView.spec.ts</path>
      <reason>Frontend tests: empty backlog guidance, task selector rendering, date picker, create mutation body assertion, edit modal for referenced card (read-only), edit modal for unreferenced card (free-form fields). Uses capturing spies for mutation assertions.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>frontend/src/calendar/DailySchedule.vue</path>
      <reason>Displays "From backlog" badge when taskId is present on a card.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>frontend/src/calendar/composables/useDailySchedule.ts</path>
      <password>true</password>
      <reason>Type definition for ScheduleTaskCard now includes taskId: string | null.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>frontend/src/client/types.gen.ts</path>
      <reason>Generated client types — includes taskId as optional string in CreateScheduleCardRequestBody and required string | null in TaskCard response.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>frontend/openapi-snapshot.json</path>
      <reason>OpenAPI spec snapshot — taskId field added to request and response schemas.</reason>
    </code_area>
  </relevant_code_areas>

  <planner_constraints>
    <constraint>The two critical correctness bugs (UpdateScheduleCard field erasure, DeleteTask 500 → 400) identified in earlier reviews have been fixed at HEAD c0e3997. The planner should treat these as resolved unless re-verification finds otherwise.</constraint>
    <constraint>The most recent review round (Comment 1, swarm-reviewer, 2026-06-16T20:36:27Z) approves the PR and recommends merge. However, Comment 2 (swarm-lead-dev, 2026-06-16T20:35:59Z) has a later outcome of needs_work with four unresolved concerns. The planner must reconcile these.</constraint>
    <constraint>There is no interactive user available. All execution must run through Docker-backed scripts.</constraint>
    <constraint>Project verification script is at scripts/precommit-run. Must pass before claiming completion.</constraint>
  </planner_constraints>

  <assumptions>
    <assumption>The TOCTOU race in inheritance resolution (Comment 2, point 1) is low practical risk because the FK constraint (ON DELETE RESTRICT) prevents deletion of the referenced task between the read and the write. The only risk is stale inherited values if the task is modified concurrently, which is a acceptable in a single-user/small-team workflow.</assumption>
    <assumption>The silent taskId-clearing path (Comment 2, point 2) is not triggered by the current frontend code, which always sends taskId for referenced cards. It would only affect direct API callers. Whether to fix this depends on the desired contract: should a PUT with no taskId preserve the existing reference, or clear it?</assumption>
    <assumption>Mock store inconsistencies (Comment 2, point 3) are minimal at HEAD c0e3997. The mock store's CreateScheduleCard/UpdateScheduleCard inheritance logic mirrors the real store. The scheduleTaskRefs map maintains consistency.</assumption>
    <assumption>Missing architecture documentation (Comment 3, point) is out of scope for code-focused implementation work and can be deferred or handled separately.</assumption>
  </assumptions>

  <open_questions>
    <question>Should UpdateScheduleCard preserve the existing taskId when input.TaskId is empty (silent clearing protection)? The current code writes an empty taskId when the input doesn't contain one. The frontend always sends taskId for referenced cards, but direct API callers could lose the reference. Decision needed on whether this is a bug or by-design.</question>
    <question>Should the inheritance resolution (GetTaskByIDForRef) be moved inside the database transaction to eliminate the TOCTOU window? This would require running the SELECT inside the pgx tx, which adds tx complexity but closes the race.</question>
    <question>Are there any other gate-agent items (from the Comment 2 needs_work) that the latest reviewer comment (Comment 1 approved) did not address? The approved message says "all requirements satisfied" and "two critical bugs" (referring to the issues from earlier rounds), but does not explicitly address the TOCTOU/mock/edge-case concerns raised in Comment 2.</question>
  </open_questions>

  <recommended_validation>
    <step>Run `cd backend && go test ./... -count=1` to verify all backend tests pass.</step>
    <step>Run `cd frontend && npx vitest run` to verify all frontend tests pass.</step>
    <step>Run `scripts/precommit-run` from project root to verify pre-commit hooks.</step>
    <step>Manually trace the UpdateScheduleCard path: verify that when a taskId-linked card is edited with only scheduledDate + assignedTo in the body, the response includes inherited title/priority/roomArea/peopleNeeded from the referenced task.</step>
    <step>Manually trace the DeleteTask path: verify that deleting a task with referencing schedule cards returns HTTP 400 (not 500) with a clear error message.</step>
    <step>Verify that editing an unreferenced (legacy) schedule card in the frontend shows free-form fields (title, priority, room/area, people needed) and submits them correctly.</step>
    <step>Verify that editing a referenced (taskId-linked) schedule card in the frontend shows read-only task info with "From backlog" badge, and that submitting changes preserves the inherited field values.</step>
  </recommended_validation>
</planning_inputs>
