<planning_inputs>
  <summary>
    <goal>Complete Daily Schedule design alignment — all implementation work is done, all blocking review feedback addressed in follow-up commits. The only remaining item is an optional info-level style normalization in route test assertions (Comment 1). No blocking or substantive changes required.</goal>
    <diff_summary>
Branch `feature/29534381-9c4d-4aa3-9fb0-4ecff9210a15` (15 commits on top of main). The Daily Schedule design work spans 4 commits:
- `392ddae` feat: Daily Schedule design — restructured DailySchedule.vue with compact header row, simplified task card anatomy (no Avatar, no CardHeader/CardTitle, comma-separated initials), compact day headers, `min-w-[260px]` / `gap-3` grid, readOnly-gated Edit/Delete/Add-task controls, pagination bar (page/totalPages/dateRangeLabel emits + Previous/Next buttons), task-backlog integration in CalendarView (task selector, search filter, read-only task display in edit mode).
- `1b4fbaa` fix: restore frontend/package-lock.json accidentally deleted (+10,667 lines restored)
- `d03fc3e` fix: resolve review feedback — Card gap-panel spacing (`!gap-0` on Card wrapper in DailySchedule.vue, line 74) and route test Edit/Delete assertions (calendar route now asserts `toContain("Edit")` and `toContain("Delete")`, home route asserts `not.toContain(">Edit<")` and `not.toContain(">Delete<")` plus pagination button disabled check)
- `3b88aa8` chore: commit task artifacts (OpenSpec change files under openspec/changes/daily-schedule-design-alignment/)

Key files changed in the design commits:
- `frontend/src/calendar/DailySchedule.vue`: +64/−41 lines, component restructured per spec
- `frontend/src/calendar/CalendarView.vue`: +164/−70 lines, task-backlog integration, pagination prop/emit passthrough
- `frontend/src/home/HomeView.vue`: +23/−2 lines, pagination prop/emit passthrough, read-only mode
- `frontend/tests/app-routes-render.test.ts`: +18/−7 lines, pagination + Edit/Delete assertions added
- `frontend/tests/calendar/DailySchedule.test.ts`: +229/−12 lines, compact anatomy + pagination bar tests
- `frontend/package-lock.json`: restored in fix commit, minor version bumps in d03fc3e (+32/−32)
93 files changed total, +7012/−686 lines across the branch.
    </diff_summary>
    <durable_task_comment_status>present</durable_task_comment_status>
  </summary>

  <review_feedback>
    <!-- All 5 task comments. Ordered chronologically (oldest to newest). -->
    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-lead-dev</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>cc753650-981f-4146-91f0-243bb3da5762</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-17T19:36:52Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>Two gaps: (1) route-level integration tests are missing (called out in the Daily Schedule design alignment spec), (2) Card gap-panel creates redundant spacing between header and content regions.</request>
      <impacted_code>frontend/tests/app-routes-render.test.ts, frontend/src/calendar/DailySchedule.vue (Card wrapper)</impacted_code>
      <notes>Outcome: approved. Addressed in commit d03fc3e: Edit/Delete assertions added to calendar route (~line 308-309), `!gap-0` class added to Card wrapper (line 74), pagination Previous-disabled check added to home route (~line 348).</notes>
    </item>

    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-reviewer</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>f136421e-c5e1-48db-81c6-9cda14339efc</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-17T19:37:42Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>CRITICAL: frontend/package-lock.json was deleted in commit 392ddae, breaking reproducible builds. Must be reverted before merging.</request>
      <impacted_code>frontend/package-lock.json</impacted_code>
      <notes>Outcome: needs_work. RESOLVED in commit 1b4fbaa: file restored with full 10,667 lines from main. No longer blocking.</notes>
    </item>

    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-architect</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>771b4cde-fac8-4bd7-b0cf-a1f43c52e667</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-17T19:46:06Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>No changes requested. Confirmed: component boundaries, dependency direction, data flow contracts, read-only vs. editable separation, and Card `!gap-0` override all correct. No architectural drift, circular dependencies, or boundary violations.</request>
      <impacted_code>None (structural review only)</impacted_code>
      <notes>Outcome: approved. Pure validation — zero action items.</notes>
    </item>

    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-lead-dev</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>324461ad-22ce-4b19-94f5-7fce2a58224f</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-17T19:46:46Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>Two non-blocking architectural concerns flagged for attention: (1) brittle `!important` gap override pattern on Card component, (2) test assertion specificity in route tests. Neither blocks approval.</request>
      <impacted_code>frontend/src/calendar/DailySchedule.vue:74, frontend/tests/app-routes-render.test.ts</impacted_code>
      <notes>Outcome: approved. The `!important` pattern is an acknowledged trade-off (Card creates intrinsic vertical gap that DailySchedule manages internally). Test assertion specificity concern elaborated in Comment 1. Neither item requires action for merge.</notes>
    </item>

    <item>
      <source>task_comment</source>
      <source_metadata>
        <author>swarm-reviewer</author>
        <comment_source>agent_run</comment_source>
        <agent_run_id>42f9c422-2455-4cf2-9b76-4d418e229347</agent_run_id>
        <created_at>2026-06-17T19:47:43Z</created_at>
      </source_metadata>
      <request>INFO-level style suggestion: normalize assertion precision between calendar and home route tests. Calendar route uses `toContain("Edit")` (plain text, line 308) while home route uses `not.toContain(">Edit<")` (HTML element tag, line 339). Suggestion: change calendar route to `toContain(">Edit<")` for consistency. Explicitly noted as "minor style preference, does not affect correctness."</request>
      <impacted_code>frontend/tests/app-routes-render.test.ts:308-309</impacted_code>
      <notes>Outcome: approved. This is the ONLY remaining unresolved feedback item. Severity: [info]. All 8 functional requirements from the design alignment spec are satisfied. All 242 tests pass including 36 tests covering the changed component and routes. No merge conflicts.</notes>
    </item>
  </review_feedback>

  <relevant_code_areas>
    <code_area>
      <path>frontend/tests/app-routes-render.test.ts</path>
      <reason>Only file with an unresolved item. Lines 308-309 use `toContain("Edit")` / `toContain("Delete")` where lines 339-340 use `not.toContain(">Edit<")` / `not.toContain(">Delete<")`. The suggestion is to change the calendar route's positive assertions to use the `>Tag<` form for consistency. This is purely cosmetic.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>frontend/src/calendar/DailySchedule.vue</path>
      <reason>Primary implementation file. No changes needed — all review feedback addressed. Line 74 (`<Card class="!gap-0 relative">`) resolves the Card gap-panel spacing issue from Comment 5. The `!important` pattern flagged in Comment 2 is an accepted trade-off.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>frontend/package-lock.json</path>
      <reason>Verified restored — commit 1b4fbaa restored the full 10,667-line lockfile. Commit d03fc3e applied minor version bumps (+32/−32 lines). No integrity issues remain.</reason>
    </code_area>
    <code_area>
      <path>frontend/tests/calendar/DailySchedule.test.ts</path>
      <reason>Expanded with 229 lines of new tests covering compact header anatomy, simplified card anatomy (initials-only, no Avatar), pagination bar rendering, boundary button disabled states, and readOnly read/write control gating. All pass. No changes needed.</reason>
    </code_area>
  </relevant_code_areas>

  <planner_constraints>
    <constraint>Do NOT modify DailySchedule.vue component logic or template structure — the implementation is approved by all 4 reviewers and matches the OpenSpec design alignment spec.</constraint>
    <constraint>Do NOT modify package-lock.json — it is already restored and correct.</constraint>
    <constraint>If the optional style normalization is applied, change ONLY lines 308-309 of app-routes-render.test.ts: `toContain("Edit")` → `toContain(">Edit<")` and `toContain("Delete")` → `toContain(">Delete<")`. No other test changes.</constraint>
    <constraint>Run `scripts/precommit-run` after any change to verify all checks pass.</constraint>
    <constraint>The existing `planning_inputs.xml` file at repo root was written for a DIFFERENT task (pagination composable tests, branch `feature/213bc642`) with different agent run IDs. It is stale and incorrect for this task. This file replaces it.</constraint>
  </planner_constraints>

  <assumptions>
    <assumption>The Daily Schedule design alignment implementation is correct and complete. Three of the five task comments (Comments 2, 3, and 5) are `approved` with zero action items. Comment 4 (`needs_work` for package-lock.json deletion) is resolved by commit 1b4fbaa. Comment 1 (`approved`) carries a single info-level style note.</assumption>
    <assumption>The info-level style suggestion in Comment 1 is truly optional. The reviewer explicitly states "minor style preference and does not affect correctness." A planner may choose to skip this item entirely without violating any requirement.</assumption>
    <assumption>All 242 tests pass on the current branch HEAD (`d03fc3e`). The `!gap-0` override works as intended, and the route-test assertions cover the required Edit/Delete gating.</assumption>
  </assumptions>

  <open_questions>
    <question>Should the Calendar route assertion style normalization be applied (Comment 1) or skipped? The feedback is [info] severity with no correctness impact. Applying it is a 2-line change in one file; skipping it means the task is finished as-is.</question>
    <question>Is there any CI or merge-blocking check that enforces test assertion style consistency? If not, this is purely cosmetic and can be deferred indefinitely.</question>
  </open_questions>

  <recommended_validation>
    <step>Run `cd frontend && npx vitest run tests/app-routes-render.test.ts` to confirm all route assertions pass on current HEAD.</step>
    <step>Run `cd frontend && npx vitest run` to confirm full test suite passes (242 tests).</step>
    <step>Run `scripts/precommit-run` from repo root to verify all automated checks pass.</step>
    <step>If the optional style normalization is applied, re-run the route test to confirm `toContain(">Edit<")` matches the rendered HTML.</step>
  </recommended_validation>
</planning_inputs>
